DAVID METCALF

Sacramento, CA 95816

<u>LinkedIn.com/in/david-codes</u> | <u>GitHub.com/gloriousLoaf</u> | Portfolio: <u>Metcalf.dev</u> Contact available on Portfolio site

SUMMARY

I am a full stack web developer and teach programming to beginning coders. I've completed a 24 week MERN full stack development certificate through UC Davis and am passionate about building modern, responsive web and platform experiences. My career experience includes web development, managing teams, ecommerce, sales and social media marketing.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript ES6+, Typescript, CSS3, HTML5, SQL, NoSQL

Applications: GitHub, MongoDB, MySQL Workbench, Robo 3T, VS Code, Git Bash, Postman

Tools: Mongoose, Express, React, Next, Node, Handlebars, JSX, jQuery, Bootstrap

Concepts: Functional & OOP, ORM, MVC, algorithm design, agile and scrum methodology

PROJECTS

CartMe | github.com/gloriousLoaf/CartMe | cart-me.herokuapp.com

- A full stack ecommerce site with shopping cart, reviews, user profiles and admin roles.
- State managed with React-Redux store, encrypted authorization with JSON web tokens, and user payments through PayPal API sandbox that can convert to live payments.
- Tools: React, Redux, React-Bootstrap, Bcrypt, Web Tokens, MongoDB, Express, Node

Emoji Runner | github.com/gloriousLoaf/Emoji-Runner | emoji-runner.herokuapp.com

- A classic runner game with soundtrack and effects, secure login and score tracking.
- I engineered the in-game physics, progression, canvas, scoreboard and user interface.
- Tools: P5.js, MySQL, Express, Node, Handlebars & Sequelizer

Covid-19 Tracker | github.com/gloriousLoaf/Covid-19-Tracker | metcalf.dev/Covid-19-Tracker

- App that allows users to track global & local stats, testing info, and interactive map.
- I developed the API calls and logic for stats, news, local testing sites, and resources.
- Tools: jQuery, jQueryUI, AJAX, Mapbox, IPAPI, Moment.js

EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer - Contractor Launch Partner

05/2021 - Present Remote / Austin, TX

Building and maintaining MERN web apps for early phase startup clients. *Key Accomplishments:*

- Turn UX/UI designs and wireframes into full, responsive apps
- Refactoring and optimizing code for best practices and performance enhancements
- Develop User Stories into features through all parts of the stack

Frontend Developer - Contractor MLtwist

12/2020 – Present

Remote / Sacramento, CA

Building presentational and smart components for MLtwist.com, a Machine Learning SaaS. *Key Accomplishments:*

- Creating Next.js components in TypeScript following the UX design plan
- Connecting stateful components to backend by writing custom API

Remote Tutor, Full Stack Web Development 2U Inc. / Trilogy Education Coding Boot Camps

11/2020 - 05/2021

Remote

Live one-on-one video tutoring sessions with boot camp students learning web development. *Key Accomplishments:*

- Providing educational and motivational support to students on a wide range of topics
- Coach and guide students through problem solving, debugging and online research
- Schedule, manage and host sessions through Calendly and Zoom, follow up via Slack

Tasting Room and eCommerce Manager Domaine de la Terre Rouge

2017 - 2019

Plymouth, CA

Oversaw all DTC operations of a 20,000 case production winery, including ecommerce *Kev Accomplishments:*

- Grew online sales by 10%, customer email database by 20%, and implemented regular data hygiene and auditing for maximized efficiency
- Lead our service team to amplify online and in-store revenue while streamlining payment processing
- Programmed retargeting tactics that deployed social media and web traffic analytics

EDUCATION

Full Stack Development Certificate: University of California, Davis

2020

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, the MERN stack, Git version control, accessibility and mobile responsiveness. Delivered 23 polished and functional web products, including three group projects. Repositories were reviewed for best practices, readability and maintainability.

Wine Business Management Certificate: California State University, Sonoma 2015

A year-long specialized program focused on mastering the management and direction of a profitable wine production business. This included vineyard management, winery planning and zoning, harvest, fermentation and ageing, bottling, warehousing, digital marketing, online sales, website management, CRM deployment and legal compliance per taxation and transportation.